Senior Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Skilled software engineer focused in server and back-end development on teams practicing Agile Methodologies. Expertise includes Java, git, Atlassian utilities, unit testing with mocks, continuous integration, server architecture, performance testing, Linux server diagnostics, server virtualization, integration testing, automation scripting, and requirement analysis.

PROFICIENCIES

Java - 11 years

Spring, Hibernate, OSGi, JUnit, CXF, JDBC, ServiceMix, Maven, JMockit, Camel Atlassian Development Utilities - 5 years

Stash, Jira, Bamboo, Confluence, FishEye

SQL - 11 years

Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server, JAXB, Hibernate ORM

NoSQL - 1 year

MongoDB, Redis, Cassandra, Hibernate OGM

Virtualization - 4 years

Docker, Amazon EC2, Oracle VirtualBox, VMware vCloud, VMware Workstation *Linux - 7 years*

Server management, Bash scripting, Python, performance monitoring Development Toolkits - 11 years

Git, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Subversion, Ant, SecureCRT, Babun, Cygwin *Front-End Web - 3 years*

SPA, AngularJS, JQuery, Javascript, HTML 5, CSS, Struts, Velocity Security Mitigation - 8 years

SSL, WireShark, salted hashing/encryption, firewall configuration Server Clustering and Disaster Recovery - 8 years

Geo-redundancy, Active/Active, Active/Passive, recovery analysis *Performance Testing - 4 years*

JMeter, Thread Dump Analyzer, Garbage Collection Viewer, JConsole Endpoint Management - 3 years

APNS, GCM, XMPP, Ejabberd, Erlang

Continuous Integration - 5 years

Bamboo, Jenkins, Hudson

Deployment Support and Diagnostics - 4 years

WireShark, JConsole, GCViewer, IBM Thread Dump Analyzer

Zach Calvert

EXPERIENCE

TEKsystemsDallas, TX
March 2016 - Current
Contractor for TEKsystems as Java Technical Lead at Southwest Airlines leading a
team of developers managing a passenger data service which exposes persisted
content via SOAP APIs and consuming messages off of a bridged Message Queue
built on JMS. Technologies include CXF SOAP, JMS MQ, git, JAXB, Oracle, Tomcat,
and Python for service deployment automation.

XpressDocs Fort Worth, TX *July 2015 - March 2016* Responsible for migrating a team from waterfall development to Agile Methodologies. Provided development leadership in updating products from Java 6 to Java 8, Ant to Maven, develop CI and CD Jenkins builds, work with IT to deliver JMX monitoring touch points, and aid in developing Jira workflow to meet our team's needs. Independently developed an integration service API that provided a 750% performance improvement in CASS and NCOA address validations.

Dynamit Fort Worth, TX *April 2015 - June 2015* Developed a Hippo-CMS server Tomcat base complete with custom REST services. Technologies used include Jenkins, Maven, IntelliJ, Git, JMeter, Jira, and Oracle Virtual Box. Responsible for performance testing, initial project architecture, REST service implementation, and unit testing.

Alcatel-Lucent, Contractor Austin, TX June 2009 - April 2015 Provided software contracting services for server development within the telecommunications industries including mobile endpoint management, call prevention services, mobile fix-it services, and electric smart metering network solutions. Responsible for service architecture and implementations including mobile messaging, cluster architecture, and disaster recovery. Technologies used include Spring-DM, Hibernate ORM, OSGi, JMeter, Eclipse IDE, Apache ServiceMix, Camel, Subversion, JConsole, Wireshark, Linux, Solaris, and ejabberd.

TransUnion Austin, TX *January 2005 - April 2009* Implemented server and desktop solutions for the real estate industry including automated flood zone determination software, floodplain research utilities, flood zone certificate point-of-sale, and home appraisal server. Technologies used include Apache Struts, OSGi, JUnit, SOAP, JNI, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, and RCP.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Arlington

January 2000 - December 2004

Graduated summa cum laude with a Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering